Guide to the R. Stuart Hummel Family Papers M1607
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series III. ARTHUR W. HUMMEL SR. FAMILY PAPERS, 1900-2001
  - Subseries I. ARTHUR W. HUMMEL SR. DIARIES and SUBJECT FILES
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., published writings (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., published writings (Box 158, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., published writings (Box 158, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., book reviews (Box 158, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., Library of Congress, miscellaneous materials (Box 158, Folder 11)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., Library of Congress, Division of Orientalia: catalogs of materials added to the collection, 1927-1935 (Box 158, Folder 12)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., Library of Congress, Division of Orientalia: catalogs of materials added to the collection, 1936-1940 (Box 158, Folder 13)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., Library of Congress, Quarterly of Current Acquisitions: includes article, "The Growth of the Orientalia Collections", February 1954 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., list of publications acquired for the Library of Congress (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., National Geographic Magazine: article on the Library of Congress with photo of Arthur W. Hummel Sr. on page 664, May 1950 (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., Arthur W. Hummel Sr., transcription of recorded autobiography, circa 1968-1969 (Box 159, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., obituary by Edwin and Janet Beale, published in the Journal of Asian Studies, February 1976 (Box 159, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 159, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 159, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 159, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 159, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 160, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr., biographical materials (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II. ARTHUR W. HUMMEL SR. CORRESPONDENCE
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. and Elaine Atwood, circa 1968-1981 (Box 161, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. and Elaine Atwood, circa 1968-1981 (Box 161, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, circa 1904-1954 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, circa 1927-1938 (Box 162, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, circa 1940-1949 (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, circa 1950-1954 (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1955-1956 (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1955-1956 (Box 162, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1957 (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1958 (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1959 January-April (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1959 August-December (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1960 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1961 (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1962 January-June (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1962 July-December (Box 163, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1963 January-June (Box 163, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1963 July-December (Box 163, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1964 January-June (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1964 July-December (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1965 January-April (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1965 May-July (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1965 August-December (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1966 January-April (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1966 May-August (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1966 September-December (Box 164, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1967 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1967 January-February (Box 165, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1967 March-April (Box 165, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1967 May-June (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1967 July-August (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1967 September-October (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1967 November-December (Box 165, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1968-1969 (Box 165, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1968 January-April (Box 165, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1968 May-June (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1968 July-September (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1968 October-December (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1969 January-February (Box 165, Folder 13)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1969 March-May (Box 165, Folder 14)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1969 June-July (Box 165, Folder 15)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1969 August-October (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1969 November-December (Box 166, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1970 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1970 January-March (Box 166, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1970 April-June (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1970 July-September (Box 166, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1971 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1971 May-June (Box 166, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1971 July-August (Box 166, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1971 September-October (Box 166, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1971 November-December (Box 166, Folder 11)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1972 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1972 January-February (Box 167, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1972 March-April (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1972 May-June (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1972 July-August (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1972 September-October (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1972 November-December (Box 167, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1973 (Box 167, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, January-March 1973 (Box 167, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, April-June 1973 (Box 167, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, July-September 1973 (Box 167, Folder 11)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, October-December 1973 (Box 167, Folder 12)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous materials, 1974 (Box 167A, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1974 January-March (Box 167A, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1974 April-June (Box 167A, Folder 3)
      - Letter 1 (Box 167A, Folder 3, Item 1)
      - Letter 2 (Box 167A, Folder 3, Item 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1974 July-September (Box 167A, Folder 4)
      - Letter 1 (Box 167A, Folder 4, Item 1)
      - Letter 2 (Box 167A, Folder 4, Item 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, 1974 October-December (Box 167A, Folder 5)
      - Letter 1 (Box 167A, Folder 5, Item 1)
      - Letter 2 (Box 167A, Folder 5, Item 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous clippings, circa 1956-1962 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to William F. Hummel, miscellaneous clippings, circa 1963-1966 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Sr. to Martha Solter, 1904-1954 (Box 168, Folder 3)
  - Subseries III. RUTH BOOKWALTER HUMMEL
    - Ruth Bookwalter Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel, 1915-1942 (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - Ruth Bookwalter Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel, 1944-1947 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - Ruth Bookwalter Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel, 1951-1956 (Box 168, Folder 6)
    - Ruth Bookwalter Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel, 1957-1966 (Box 168, Folder 7)
    - Ruth Bookwalter Hummel, biographical materials (Box 168, Folder 8)
  - Subseries IV: ARTHUR W. HUMMEL JR.
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr. and Betty Lou Hummel to R. Stuart Hummel, circa 1966-2000 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., typescript biography by Anita Hummel, circa 1985 (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., interview, Foreign Affairs Oral History Collection, 1989 (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., interview, Foreign Affairs Oral History Collection, 1994 (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1941-1965 (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1941-1965 (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1966-1975 (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1966-1975 (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1976-1985 (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1986-2000 (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 1986-2000 (Box 170, Folder 10)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 2001-2007 (Box 170, Folder 11)
    - Arthur W. Hummel Jr., biographical materials, 2001-2007 (Box 170, Folder 12)
  - Subseries V. SHARMAN B. HUMMEL and CAROL HUMMEL AMES
    - Sharman B. Hummel family, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Sharman B. Hummel family, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 2)
    - Sharman B. Hummel family, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - Sharman B. Hummel family, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 4)
    - Carol Hummel Ames, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 5)
    - Carol Hummel Ames, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 6)
    - Carol Hummel Ames, photographs (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - Linda and Larry Ames, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 8)
    - Linda and Larry Ames, biographical materials (Box 171, Folder 9)
- Series IV. R. STUART HUMMEL PERSONAL MATERIALS and SUBJECT FILES, 1915-2006
  This series contains R. Stuart Hummel's juvenilia, materials related to his education and hobbies, biographical and miscellaneous materials, as well materials relating to his children and grandchildren.
  As this series contains mostly biographical materials, photocopies, and ephemera, only a few select items have been made available online.
  - Subseries I. MEMOROBILIA and EDUCATION
    - R. Stuart Hummel, birth certificate and related materials, September 30, 1915 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Little Light Bearers certificate, October 30, 1915 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Baby's Book, circa 1915 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, early memorabilia (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, early memorabilia (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, grammar school assignments (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, early writings (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, early writings (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, composition books (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, self-study notebook (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Manual Arts High School, Botany class, 1930 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Manual Arts High School, "The Spectator"; "The Song" (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, "Manual Arts Daily" (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, "Manual Arts Daily" (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, The Artisan, Manual Arts High School yearbook, 1934 (Box 173, Folder 5)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, report cards, circa 1933-1938 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, autograph album, circa 1937-1938 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous certificates, 1940-1971 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, graduate school records, 1951-1967 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, "Sino-Vietnamese Relations and the Sino-Soviet Dispute", 1964 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, coursework, "International Politics", 1966 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, coursework, "Modern Far Eastern History", 1966 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, coursework, "International Politics", 1967 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, "Public Opinion and Foreign Policy", 1967 (Box 174, Folder 9)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous teaching methods (Box 174, Folder 10)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, bibles (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, postcard album (Flat-box 243)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, New York Explorer’s Club (Box 242, Folder 10)
    - R Stuart Hummel, Filmmaking (Box 242, Folder 11)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Readex Bookrest (Box 248, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Readex Bookrest (Box 248, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Readex Bookrest (Box 248, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, Readex Bookrest (Box 248, Folder 4)
    - R Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous handwritten recollections (Box 242, Folder 12)
  - Subseries II. BIOGRAPHICAL and MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 6)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, biographical materials (Box 175, Folder 8)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - R. Stuart Hummel, miscellaneous materials (Box 177, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III. CHILDREN and GRANDCHILDREN
    - William M. Hummel, photographs, circa 1960-1990 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - William M. Hummel, photographs, circa 1970 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - William M. Hummel, biographical materials (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - William M. Hummel, biographical materials (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - William M. Hummel, biographical materials (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - William M. Hummel, biographical materials (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - William M. Hummel, biographical materials (Box 178, Folder 7)
    - John and Masayo Kessler, photographs (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - John and Masayo Kessler, photographs (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - John and Masayo Kessler, photographs (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - John and Masayo Kessler, photographs (Box 179, Folder 4)
- Series V. R. STUART HUMMEL DIARIES, 1932-2006
  This series contains R. Stuart's diaries. R. Stuart wrote a diary entry, documenting every day of his life, beginning in 1932 through 2006, shortly before his death. Early diaries are handwritten, but from 1945 on diaries are typed. All the diaries are bound and include numerous attached clippings, photographs, and ephemera. Also includes photo diary of work in Asia for the U.S. State Department.
  Note: From 1943 to 1944, R. Stuart wrote daily letters to his wife Kathleen rather than keeping a diary. See also Hawaii Correspondence 1943-1944
  R Stuart Hummel’s diaries through 1970 are available online. The diaries were scanned page by page; however, the diaries contain many folded-in and attached items (i.e. news clippings, greeting cards) that may not have been scanned in their entirety.
  - Diary, 1932 (Box 22, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1933 (Box 22, Volume 2)
  - Diary, 1934 (Box 22, Volume 3)
  - Diary, 1935 (Box 22, Volume 4)
  - Diary, 1936 (Box 23, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1937 (Box 23, Volume 2)
  - Diary, 1938 (Box 23, Volume 3)
  - Diary, 1939 (Box 23, Volume 4)
  - Diary, 1940 (Box 24, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1941 (Box 24, Volume 2)
  - Diary, 1942 (Box 24, Volume 3)
  - Diary, 1944 (Box 24, Volume 4)
  - Diary, 1945 (Box 25, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1946 (Box 26, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1947 (Box 27, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1948 (Box 28, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1949 (Box 29, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1950 (Box 30, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1951 (Box 31, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1952 (Box 32, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1952 (Box 33, Volume 1)
  - Photo diary, volume 1: photographs of travels in Asia, 1952 (Box 34, Volume 1)
  - Photo diary, volume 2: photographs of travels in Asia and Europe, 1952 (Box 35, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1953 (Box 36, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1954 (Box 37, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1955 (Box 38, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1956-1957 (Box 39, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1958-1959 (Box 40, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1960 (Box 41, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1960 (Box 42, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1961 (Box 43, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1961 (Box 44, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1962 (Box 45, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1962 (Box 46, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1963 (Box 47, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1963 (Box 48, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1964 (Box 49, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1964 (Box 50, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1965 (Box 51, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1965 (Box 52, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 3, 1965 (Box 53, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1966 (Box 54, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1967 (Box 55, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1967 (Box 56, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 3, 1967 (Box 57, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1968 (Box 58, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1968 (Box 59, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 3, 1968 (Box 60, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1969 (Box 61, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1969 (Box 61, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 3, 1969 (Box 62, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 4, 1969 (Box 62, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1970 (Box 63, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1970 (Box 63, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 3, 1970 (Box 64, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 4, 1970 (Box 65, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1971 (Box 66, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1971 (Box 66, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1972 (Box 67, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1972 (Box 68, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1973 (Box 69, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1974 (Box 70, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1975 (Box 71, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1976 (Box 72, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1977 (Box 73, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1978 (Box 74, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1979 (Box 75, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1980 (Box 76, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1981 (Box 77, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1981 (Box 78, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1982 (Box 79, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1982 (Box 79, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 1, 1983 (Box 80, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 1983 (Box 80, Volume 2)
  - Diary, 1984 (Box 81, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1985 (Box 82, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1986 (Box 83, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1987 (Box 84, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1988 (Box 85, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1989 (Box 86, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1990 (Box 87, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1991 (Box 88, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1992 (Box 89, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1993 (Box 90, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1994 (Box 91, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1995 (Box 92, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1996 (Box 93, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1997 (Box 94, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1998 (Box 95, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 1999 (Box 96, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 2000 (Box 97, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 2001 (Box 98, Volume 1)
  - Diary, 2002 (Box 99, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 1, 2003 (Box 100, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 2003 (Box 100, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 1, 2004 (Box 101, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 2004 (Box 101, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 1, 2005 (Box 102, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 2005 (Box 102, Volume 2)
  - Diary, volume 1, 2006 (Box 103, Volume 1)
  - Diary, volume 2, 2006 (Box 103, Volume 2)
- Series VI. R. STUART HUMMEL CORRESPONDENCE, 1937-2006
  This series is divided into four subseries:
  Subseries I: Family Correspondence: correspondence with his parents, Mildred Stuart Hummel and William F. Hummel, arranged chronologically, first by outgoing and then by incoming letters; mixed correspondence with other family members arranged alphabetically; also includes miscellaneous materials found with correspondence.
  Subseries II. Hawaii Correspondence: bound letters written to Kathleen Merrett Hummel while R. Stuart was stationed in Honolulu, Hawaii during World War II.
  Subseries III. Kathleen Merrett Hummel Correspondence: outgoing letters from Kathleen Merrett Hummel to her husband R. Stuart Hummel and to R. Stuart’s parents, William and Mildred Hummel.
  Subseries IV. Miscellaneous Correspondence: all remaining correspondence, including correspondence with friends and colleagues, arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent; also miscellaneous and mixed correspondence found loose.
  R. Stuart’s letters to his grandmother, Rachel Anna Golden Stuart, through 1946, and to his parents through 1976 are available online. Also available are letters he sent to his wife Kathleen, when stationed in Hawaii during World War II, as well as more recent correspondence with Paul Illick regarding the Nanking Incident of 1927.
  - Subseries I. FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - R. Stuart Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel and William F. Hummel, 1944-1945 (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - R. Stuart Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel and William F. Hummel, 1946-1949 (Box 184, Folder 2)
    - R. Stuart Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel and William F. Hummel, 1950-1951 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    - R. Stuart Hummel to Mildred Stuart Hummel and William F. Hummel, 1952-1953 (Box 184, Folder 4)